{
    "id": "cea24e1321d94fbeb5c275d993867376",
    "title": "Although, Though, Despite, In Spite Of, and However | Grammar Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "a35e68f0db764e51ae7ec03da9249791",
            "title": "Although, Though, Despite, and However",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "............................ the watch was expensive, he bought it.",
                    "description": "Although is a conjunction. We use it before a clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Although",
                        "Despite",
                        "However"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We went out ................................... the rain.",
                    "description": "The prepositions 'despite' and 'in spite of' are interchangeable. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "in spite of",
                        "despite",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "We went out ............................... it was raining.",
                    "description": "We use 'although' before a clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "although",
                        "however",
                        "despite"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "............................ my husband didn't like the movie, I enjoyed it a lot.",
                    "description": "The conjunctions 'though' and 'although' are interchangeable. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Although",
                        "Though",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "He passed the test. ............................, he didn't get the job.",
                    "description": "'However' is not a conjunction. It is a transitional adverb and goes at the beginning of the sentence. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Despite",
                        "Although",
                        "However"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": ".............................. he passed the test, he didn't get the job.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "In spite of",
                        "Although",
                        "However"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "They managed to do it ........................... I was not there.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "although",
                        "despite",
                        "however"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Tired ............................. he was, he went on working.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "though",
                        "however",
                        "despite"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": ".......................... hard she tried, she couldn't do it.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "Despite",
                        "However",
                        "In spite of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "................................ of the headache, I enjoyed the movie.",
                    "description": "The correct expression is 'in spite of'. It means the same as 'despite'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Despite",
                        "In spite",
                        "However"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": ".......................... I don't agree with him, I think he is honest.",
                    "description": "Although is a conjunction. We use it before a clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Although",
                        "However",
                        "Despite"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We understood him ................................ his strong accent.",
                    "description": "Despite is a preposition. It goes before a noun. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "despite",
                        "however",
                        "although"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}